Pray Somaldo

Email: praysomaldo@ymail.com Github: github.com/prays

Portfolio: prays.github.io

Mobile: 081317195001

About Me

As machine learning enthusiasts, I like to build something related to AI products. I have build computer vision products that have deployed in some retail area with python integrated to MySQL as databases using TensorRT to deploy. I also aiming to research on computer vision by following the updates on that area. On the other hand, I develop my skill by continuously learn by taking training from Kominfo and bootcamp such as Bangkit. I realized that I love learning even when I have to repeat it from zero. Thus, I always practicing my skills and like to learn something new.

EDUCATION

• Universitas Indonesia Master of Computer Science

Depok

2019 - 2020

• Universitas Indonesia Bachelor of Mathematics

Depok

Sept. 2013 - Aug. 2017

EXPERIENCE

• Sugihart Digital Imaji

Machine Learning Engineer

Duren Sawit, Jakarta Timur August 2019 - Present

- People Counting: Build computer vision models to detect person for retail industry or department store to generate visitor data and gain insight for advertising their products also classify person data into male and female for specific advertisement. Increase accuracy up to 20% with impact as more appeal to client when presented.
- Face recognition attendance system: Build face recognition for company attendance system with real time speed to monitoring employees and integrated it with Kiosk. The system speeding up the attendance checking time no more than 2 seconds with accuracy more than 97%.
- o Indonesian License plate Recognition: Build license plate recognition specific for Indonesian plate with accuracy more than 90% on different angle and robust to light condition.

Technology used: opency, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Darkflow, Yolo, TensorRT, jupyter notebook, MySQL, OCR, netron, onnx, threading

• Kurio Slipi, Jakarta

Data Science Engineer

Sept 2018 - Feb 2019

- o Sensitive Classifier: Build and test machine learning model to filter inappropriate articles start from gathering article data, labelling, pre-processing, training, testing, until make an endpoint to deploy the classifier as a service.
- Category Classifier: Build machine learning model similar to sensitive classifier, but with various category such as tech, sport, politics, gadget, e-sport, etc and validate the model to achieve up to 95% accuracy.

Technology used: pipeny, pyeny, mongoDB, jupyter notebook, docker, google cloud platform, flask, spacy, github, jira

• Metra Digital Media

Pancoran, Jakarta

Junior Data Scientist

Oct 2017 - Jan 2018

- Web Crawling: Web Crawling and update data then load it to server data using python
- Clustering: Clustering and analyze data for campaign needs and visualize it based on region by density, salary, religion, etc.
- Data Gathering: Data management and querying using SQL for report needs Technology used: SPSS, R, MySQL, jupyter notebook, zeppelin, hadoop

SKILLS

- Python: beautifulsoup, featuretools, flask, joblib, matplotlib, numpy, pandas, seaborn, scikit-learn, scipy, spacy, unittest, plotly, pyspark, request, opency, PIL, imutils, opency, threading
- R: caret, dplyr,ggplot
- Matlab: image processing
- SQL: MySQL, Postgre, NoSQL

CERTIFICATE

• Computer Vision Nanodegree

Learn about facial keypoints, image captioning, and SLAM algorithm

July 2020 Udacity

Udacity

• Deep Learning Nanodegree

Predicting bike sharing, face generation using GAN, and deploy sentiment analysis to AWS

June~2020

• Tensorflow Practice Specialization

Course from deeplearning.ai with coursera

Deeplearning.ai

June 2020

• Bangkit

An exclusive machine learning academy led by Google

Google August 2019

• Artificial Intelligence

Digitalent Scholarship in Artificial Intelligence, Fakultas Teknik UI, Depok

Kominfo, Depok

August 2019

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR

• JaidedAI/EasyOCR: Optical Character Recognition library that support 70+ languages

Publications

 Paper Symomath, Bandung

Detection of Diabetic Retinopathy on Retinal Images using Naive Bayes

2017

• Paper Still submitting

Developing Smart COVID-19 Social Distancing Surveillance Drone using YOLO

2020